MITHUN DAS

Software Engineer

Email: mithun.das227@gmail.com

Phone: +8801833994177

LinkedIn: mithun-das-4412948a

Github: mithun-Das

PROFILE

Passionate software engineer with several years of experience involved in the development of successfully delivered B2B applications implementing the standard software development procedure and cutting-edge technologies. My biggest strength is my perseverance, my enthusiasm to learn new things and doing adequate research where necessary.

WORK EXPERIENCE & PROJECTS

WebCreek(The Woodlands, USA)

Software Engineer(Remote Job)

July 2022 - Present

Softbase Application

- Developed products for US-based industrial equipment dealerships company where digital solutions were provided for their entire operations.
- Developed products using EntityFramework, MSSQL database and Angular.
- Used ASP.NET Zero framework for multi-tenant support.
- Performed Unit Testing using NUnit Framework.
- Worked in a diverse work culture where our team members were from 15+ different countries.

SELISE Digital Platform(Dhaka, Bangladesh)

Oct 2017 - Aug 2022

Software Engineer

EB-Life Global Solution

- Developed the digital product for the renowned European insurance company Swiss Life where the product was used across more than 45 countries.
- Automated some complex calculations systems like pooling simulation which used to take a huge time before our solution.
- Worked as a team lead for some particular features and designed databases(MongoDB) for large systems.
- Worked on microservice based architecture and followed the agile method for development process and implemented CQRS design pattern with event sourcing and Kafka.
- Closely involved with the client for requirement analysis.
- Involved with the deployment process in IIS server.

Malware Scanner

- Developed a malware scanning system for the renowned European insurance company IG B2B.
- Developed APIs that provide scan related history for a file to the user.
- Used .net core and RabbitMQ for backend infrastructure.

Wagile

- Developed an Event management system for a German Client.
- Used .net core and postgres for backend infrastructure.
- Used angular as frontend technology.
- Developed complex features to facilitate users to handle event management very smoothly.

SWICA

- Developed an online health product for European clients.
- Implemented notification system using signalR.
- Used agile methodology and JIRA for the development process.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C#, C, javascript, TypeScript

Backend Framework: .NET Core Frontend Framework: Angular12+ Database: MSSQL, MongoDB, Redis Unit Testing Framework: NUnit

Message Broker: Kafka

Collaboration Tools: Git, JIRA, HubStaff

EDUCATION

B.Sc.(Engineering) in Computer Science and EngineeringShahjalal University of Science and Technology
Sylhet, Bangladesh

Jan 2013 - Sep 2017

CGPA: 3.11